<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Index on Mona Maret</title>
    <link>https://www.monamaret.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index on Mona Maret</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.monamaret.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic Neovim</title>
      <link>https://www.monamaret.com/basic-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.monamaret.com/basic-neovim/</guid>
      <description>If you spend a lot of time on the command line you should consider learning how to use one of the modal text editors, like Vi or Vim. Besides the fact that it is objectively cool, Vi is included in the standard set of applications packed into the most basic and stripped-down distros of Linux. If you do a lot of systems administration you&amp;rsquo;ll eventually run into a situation where Vi is your only option, and it is kind of embarassing to panic in front of an audience if you&amp;rsquo;re fixing something in a group setting and don&amp;rsquo;t know how to, say, save and quit the file after making a change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring tmux</title>
      <link>https://www.monamaret.com/tmux-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.monamaret.com/tmux-config/</guid>
      <description>If you want to become a Tmux power user the gold standard reference is of course the wiki but it can be a bit overwhelming if you&amp;rsquo;re just getting started and are trying to figure out the basics. There are also many good beginner guides that go deep on why you might want to learn how to use Tmux and what it does for you. This page, however, is going to focus only on how to configure Tmux and some basic helpful tips, like how to copy/paste and how to scroll back through your history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing dotfiles</title>
      <link>https://www.monamaret.com/dotfiles-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.monamaret.com/dotfiles-management/</guid>
      <description>The first rule of dotfiles is don&amp;rsquo;t put anything sensitive in them, like passwords or seed words or ssh keys, if you&amp;rsquo;re going to be checking them into version control. The second rule of dotfiles is don&amp;rsquo;t put your entire damn ~./config directory into version control because that includes a lot of sensitive info and thus violates the first rule.
Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s get serious now that the warnings are out of the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Lua within Neovim configuration</title>
      <link>https://www.monamaret.com/lua-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.monamaret.com/lua-neovim/</guid>
      <description>You can use Lua script to configure Neovim, but why might you want to do that? The Vim and Neovim API are written in C, and Lua runs in the C engine; since Lua is significantly easier to write and read than C or even Vimscript, Lua can be used to write complex configuration directives.
Another more explicit reason to use it is because many useful Neovim plugins are written in Lua (like the autocompletion plugins used when setting up Neovim as an IDE) and require extensive configuration directives that can clutter up your init.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
